让我们在MATLAB中演示一些这些原理。我要创造一个点
Let’s demonstrate some of these principles in MATLAB. I’m going to create a point in
世界它将在0.3米的X方向上坐标0.2米处
the world and it’s going to be at coordinate 0.2 meters in the X direction 0.3 meters in
Y方向，Z方向5米。现在Z是方向
the Y direction and it’s going to be 5 meters in Z direction. Now Z is the direction along
相机的轴我们称之为相机的光轴。这是一个相对较小的
the axis of a camera we call the optical axis of the camera. This is a relatively small
物体距离相机5米，世界点始终是列矢量
object five meters away from the camera and a world point is always a column vector so
它就是。
there it is.
现在我要创建一个相机对象实际上是一个中心相机对象
Now I’m going to create a camera object in fact a central camera object which does
我们刚学到的特定投影，它的焦距为8
the particular projection that we just learned about and it’s got a focal length of eight
毫米。
millimetres.
所以在这里我们创建了一个工作区，现在是一个中央摄这个对象有
So here we created the workspace now a central camera projection object. This object has
有很多方法，我们将看看其中一些。但首先我是
got quite a lot of methods and we’ll have a look at some of those. But first thing I’m
要做的就是使用这个相机对象，我将投射我的世界点资本
going to do is to use this camera object and I’m going to project my world point capital
P到图像平面，你在这里看到的是我们有一些非常小的数字。
P to the image plane, what you see here is that we have got some very small numbers.
这些数字不到半毫米。我们已经看到了世界，我们已经看到了
These numbers are less than half a millimetre. We've taken our view of the world and we've
使它变得更小，更小并将其投影到图像平面上。这是件
made it much, much smaller and projected it onto the image plane. This is where the piece
电影将是或者这是数码相机芯片的所在。在这个投影中有
of film would be or this is where the digital camera chip would be. In this projection there’s
没有像素的概念，我们刚刚拍摄了世界上的图像，并用术语描述
no notion of pixels we've just taken image in the world and it’s described in terms
尺寸和距离以米为单位。我们已将它投影到图像平面和
of size and its distance in units of meters. We've projected it to the image plane and
这也是以米为单位谈论图像的大小;极少数米。
this is talking about the size of the image also in units of meters; a very small number of meters.
现在让我们把它变成数码相机让我们介绍像素的概念。我们
Now let’s turn this into a digital camera let’s introduce the notion of pixels. We’re
要创建一个新的相机对象。基本上回收这条线，我们会告诉它
going to create a new camera object. Basically recycle this line and we will tell it that
像素在一侧是10微米，因此像素是十微米宽十微米
the pixels are ten microns on a side so the pixels are square ten microns wide ten microns
高。他们的图像平面的分辨率为一千二十四平方。这个
high. And their image plane has got a resolution of one thousand and twenty four square. This
是一款百万像素摄像头。
is a mega pixel camera.
现在，如果我们看一下相机对象的参数，我们在这里可以看到焦距。
Now if we look at the parameters of our camera object we see here we can see the focal length.
在这里我们可以看到像素的大小，像素数，1024x1024正是我们输入的内容
Here we can see the size of pixels, the number of pixels, 1024 x 1024 exactly what we entered
在命令行上。而这个参数是光学所在的主要点
on the command line. And this parameter the principal point which is where the optical
穿过图像平面的轴在坐标512,512处的中间处被击打。
axis pierces the image plane is smack in the middle at coordinate 512, 512.
现在我有了我的数码相机对象，我们可以重新进行之前的投影
Now that I have my digital camera object, we can re do that projection that we had before
项目到世界点P，现在这是以像素为单位的那个点的坐标。
project to world point P and this now is the coordinate of that point in units of pixels.
相机对象的另一种方法是在图形图像平面上实际绘制这些方法
Another method of the camera object is to actually plot these on a graphical image plane
在这里，我们可以看到数码相机上投影世界点的位置
and here we can see where that world point has been projected to on the digital cameras
图像平面。所以现在我们可以看一下相机内在参数的方法。现在这个
image plane. So now the methods we can look at the cameras intrinsic parameters. Now this
是内在参数矩阵;这是整个相机投影矩阵。我们可以
is the intrinsic parameter matrix; this is the overall camera projection matrix. We can
将附加选项传递给项目函数。
pass an additional option into the project function.
第一个论点是我们的世界观点，现在我要稍微改变相机
First argument again is our world point and now I’m going to shift the camera a little
位。现在我要告诉它将摄像机沿X方向移动0.1米
bit. Now I’m going to tell it to shift the camera 0.1 meters in the X direction given
相机的坐标框架向右移动0.1米。不去
the camera’s coordinate frame that’s a shift of 0.1 meters to the right. Not going
在Y方向或Z方向上移动它，所以我们现在看到的是投影
to move it in the Y or in the Z directions so now what we see is that the projection
是不同的。我们希望，我们看到U坐标已经减少了
is different. And we would expect that, we see that the U coordinate has been reduced
从544到528，如果我们将相机向右移动，那就是我们所期望的
from 544 to 528 and that’s what we would expect if we move the camera to the right
我们希望图像平面坐标向左移动一点。
we would expect the image plane coordinate to move a bit to the left.
我们可以旋转相机，而不是翻译相机，以便我们可以旋转相机
Instead of translating the camera we could rotate the camera so we can rotate the camera
围绕Y轴。现在Y轴指向下方，所以如果我做这个0.1弧度的旋转
around the Y axis. Now the Y axis points downwards so if I do this rotation of 0.1 radians around
Y轴实际上是向右旋转相机，如果我们这样做的话
the Y axis that’s essentially rotating the camera towards the right and if we do that
这是投影再次，正如我所期望的那样，如果我将相机旋转一点
here’s the projection again and as we would expect if I rotate the camera a bit towards
右侧图像中的像素将在图像平面上向左移动一点。
the right the pixel in the image will move a bit towards the left on the image plane.
让我们考虑一个更复杂的例子，一个世界上有多个点的例子。
Let’s consider a more complex example, one where there are multiple points in the world.
要在网格模式中创建多个点，我现在将使用工具箱功能
To create multiple points in a grid pattern now I’m going to use the toolbox function
mkgrid，我想要一个2x2网格，点数在0.2米中心间隔，我想要
mkgrid and I want a 2x2 grid and the points spaced on 0.2 metre centres and I want the
网格的中心位于坐标1,2,0处。所以这是XY平面中的网格，
centre of the grid to be at a coordinate 1, 2, 0. So this is a grid in the XY plane, the
网格中心在X方向偏移1米，在Y方向偏移2米
centre of the grid is offset 1 metre in the X direction and 2 metres in the Y direction
并且所有点的Z坐标都为零。
and all the points have got a Z coordinate of zero.
所以这里是我刚刚创建的一组点，以便查看这四点
So here are the set of points that I have just created in order to view these four points
它躺在地平面上我要创造一个新的相机。这是一个中心投影
which lie on a ground plane I’m going to create a new camera. It’s a central projection
再次模型相机。我将设置默认摄像头参数，因此这是默认值
model camera again. I’m going to set default camera parameters so this is default values
用于焦距图像平面尺寸和像素尺寸。我要明确地给出姿势
for focal length image plane size and pixel size. I’m going to explicitly give the pose
相机的所以我们的四个点都躺在地面上，以便我的相机
of the camera so our four points are lying on the ground plane so in order for my camera
为了能够看到它们，它需要在一个向上俯视的地方，所以第一件事就是这样
to be able to see them it needs to be somewhere up high looking down so the first thing that
我要做的是将相机放在地面以上4米处。所以这是一个翻译
I’m going to do is to place the camera 4 metres above the ground. So this is a translation
沿着正Z轴4米，然后我将围绕Z旋转它
of 4 metres along the positive Z axis and then I’m going to rotate it around the Z
轴由Pi/3弧度组成，然后我将围绕Y轴旋转相机
axis by Pi/3 radians and then I’m going to rotate the camera around the Y axis
所以它指向地面。
so it points down at the ground.
所以只需用π弧度围绕Y轴旋转它。和我在一起，我会用这个例子
So just rotate it around the Y axis by pi radians. Bare with me I’ll work this example
这些数字应该给出类似正确的结果。
out and these numbers should give something like the right result.
我们要做的第一件事就是将这4个世界点投射到相机的图像上
First thing we’re going to do is to project those 4 world points onto the camera’s image
飞机，这里我们有这些点的坐标。所以他们显然是在内
plane and here we have the coordinates of those points. So they clearly lay within the
视野，我们实际上可以看看这四点。我们可以策划那些
field of view and we can actually have a look at those four points. And we can plot those
这就是图像平面的样子。所以他们只是在场上的边缘
and that’s what the image plane looks like. So they’re just in the edge of the field
看着我们的相机，往下看。
of view of our camera, which is looking down.
现在让我们尝试3D了解这里发生了什么，所以我要去
Now let’s try and get a 3D understanding of what’s going on here so I’m going to
创造一个新的人物。我将把它称为图二和相机上的另一种方法
create a new figure. I’m going to call it figure two and another method on the camera
我们刚创建的对象称为绘图相机。是什么让它成为3D模型
object we just created is called plot camera. What that does it to render it’s a 3D model
将相机变成图形，我要做的另一件事是添加到这些中
of a camera into a graphic and the other thing that I’m going to do is to add to these
图4给出了我的资本P的4个世界点我将把它们变成小点
graphic the 4 world points given my capital P I’m going to render them as the little
半径为0.5米的球体创造了这个小场景，打开网格
spheres with a radius of 0.5 meters each so created this little scene, turn the grid on
让它更容易看到。
to make it a bit easier to see.
如果我打开我的3D旋转工具，我可以旋转它。在这里，我们可以看到它的外观
If I turn on my 3D rotation tool I can spin this around. Here we can see what it looks
比如，这里是地平面上的四个点，然后我使用网格函数创建。
like, here are the four points on the ground plane now then I created using the grid function.
在顶部我们可以看到相机，我们可以看到相机的轴。相机是
And up the top we can see the camera and we can see the axis of the camera. Camera is
有点小。我们可以放大并查看相机，有我们
a little bit small. We can zoom in and have a look at the camera there is it, there we
可以看到它的x，y和z轴，也许放大一点，我们可以看到它，它
can see its x, y and z axis, zoom in a little bit more perhaps and we can see there, it
看起来有点像相机。这是一个正面有圆柱的盒子。这些是
looks a little bit like a camera. It’s a box with a cylinder on the front. These are
只是使用相机类中可以做的很多事情的几个例子
just the few examples of the many things that you can do using the camera classes within
工具箱。
the toolbox.